Guide to the William Bronk Papers, 1955-1989
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
William Bronk Papers
1955-1989
Bronk, William
0.2 cubic feet (1 box)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence, manuscripts, broadsides and other material by or related to William Bronk.
Biographical Note
William Bronk (1918-1999) was a significant 20th century American poet. His work garnered much acclaim, including the 1982 National Book Award.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, manuscripts, broadsides and other material by or related to William Bronk. Some of the correspondence is from James L. Weil, one of Bronk's publishers.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
William Bronk Book Collection
Subject Headings
Names:
Weil, James L.
Subjects:
Poets, American--20th century
Document Types:
Broadsides
VCL Categories
Literature and Writing
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, January 2010.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Matthew Weseley, January 2010.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to the fragility of magnetic media, the audiotapes require duplication at patron expense for use.
Container List
- Correspondence — Bronk to Matthew Weseley, 1995-1996; [7 ALS] (Folder 1)
- Correspondence — Bronk to Kevin Killian, 4 Apr 1989; [1 ALS and a William M. Bronk advertising postcard] (Folder 2)
- Correspondence — James Weil to Matthew Weseley, 1985-1986, 1975-1997; [11 items] (Folder 3)
- Manuscripts — Laura Gone, n.d.; [AMsS] (Folder 4)
- Manuscripts — Real Estate, 1987; [TMsS inscribed to Gio (Giovannina de Blasiis) and Ginny] (Folder 5)
- Manuscripts — The Primacy of Light, n.d.; [AMs, possibly sent to Giovannina de Blasiis] (Folder 6)
- Manuscripts — For and Early Italian Musician, 1955; [AMsS enc w/ ALS sent to Giovannina de Blasiis] (Folder 7)
- Broadsides — In the Beauty of the World... Providence: Burning Deck, n.d.; [signed by the author] (Folder 8)
- Broadsides — Having Come a Long Way the Wise Men Wait a Minute. Durham, NH: Friends of the University of New Hampsire Library, 1981; [Copy 18 of 50, signed by the author] (Folder 9)
- Broadsides — A Bright Day in December. Concord, NH: William B. Ewert, 1981; [Copy 29 of 36, signed by the author] (Folder 10)
- Broadsides — James Weil broadsides including The Gift, The American Cemetery, and a tribute to Bronk, All Poems Mean, [3 items, all inscribed to Matthew Weseley by the author] (Folder 11)
- Newsclippings, 1974, 1999 (Folder 12)
- Press Releases, ca. 1983, 1989; [2 items] (Folder 13)
- Photographs, [5 items] (Folder 14)
- Audiotape — Bronk Reading, 1 Jan 1997; [1 audiocassette]
- Audiotape — Bronk Reading, 24 June 1996 and 25 Aug 1986; [1 audiocassette]